Bowers, Mollie H. Collection of Arbitration and Fact Finding Decisions Regarding Police and Fire Fighters 5456
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Mollie H. Bowers Collection of Arbitration and Fact Finding Decisions Regarding Police and Fire Fighters
1967-1975
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Bowers, Mollie H.
5456
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Records (documents).
This collection consists of arbitration files and final offer cases relating to police and fire fighters.
5623346
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 18, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 13, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Mollie H. Bowers was a research consultant for the International Association of Chiefs of Police.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of arbitration files and final offer cases relating to police and fire fighters.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5140: NYS PERB Agreements 5568: Mollie H. Bowers Police and Firefighter Arbitration
Collective labor agreements -- Police; Collective labor agreements -- Fire fighters; Final offer arbitration.; Bowers, Mollie H.
5623346
- American Arbitration Association Voluntary Labor Arbitration Tribunal, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Between Fraternal Order of Police of Pittsburgh Fort Pitt Lodge No. 1 and City of Pittsburgh
- Matter of Arbitration between Livonia Police Officers Association and the City of Livonia, Michigan, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  May 9 1970
- State of Michigan Department of Labor Employment Relations Commission, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  City of Detroit, Michigan and Detroit Fire Fighters Association; May 19 1973
- State of Connecticut Labor Department Board of Labor Relations, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Various Court Cases
- Opinion of Raymond K Shields Pertaining to the Awards Granted by Arbitration in the Dispute between Local # 1338 IAFF and Shelby Twp. Board, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- State of Michigan - Michigan Employment Relations Commission, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  St. Clair County Board of Commissioners and Employees of the St. Clair County Sheriff's Department, represented by Local No. 1518, American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO, Michigan Council 55
- State of Michigan Department of Labor Employment Relations Commission, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  City of Wyandotte and Wyandotte Fire Fighters Association International Firefighters Association Local No. 356
- Compulsory Labor Arbitration Tribunal Pursuant to Michigan Public Act #312 of 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Wayne County Sheriff's Department and Deputy Sheriff's Local 502 M SEIU
- State of Michigan, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  City of Albion and Albion Fire Fighters Association, Local 1421
- The Lapeer County Board of Commissioners and American Federation of State County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME), Local No. 1421, Michigan Council 55, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  April 20 1971
- State of Michigan Employment Relations Commission Statutory Arbitration, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Flint Police Captains' Association and City of Flint, a Municipal Corporation
- City of Dearborn Michigan and Police Officers Association of Dearborn, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Lowell Police Officers Association and City of Lowell, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Matter of Arbitration between City of Detroit and Detroit Fire Fighters Association, Local 344, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  December 1 1971
- St. Clair County Board of Commissioners and American Federation of State County and Municipal Employees, Local No. 1518, Michigan Council 55, Sheriff's Department, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  November 12 1970
- Local No. 1518, American Federation of State County and Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO, Michigan Council 55 and St. Clair County Board of Commissioners, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Matter of Arbitration between City of Detroit and Detroit Fire Fighter's Association, Local 344, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Matter of Arbitration between Detroit Police Officers Association, Inc. and the City od Detroit, Michigan, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  July 1 1970
- Matter of Arbitration between Local No. 1557, International Association of Fire Fighters, AFL-CIO and the City of Sterling Heights, Michigan, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Beverly Hills Safety Officers' Association v. Village of Beverly Hills, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  January 28 1971
- Matter of Arbitration between the City of Warren, Michigan and Local Union No. 1383, Warren Firefighters Association, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Dearborn Heights Police Officers' Association v. City of Dearborn Heights, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Dearborn Heights Lieutenants, Sergeants, Corporals and Detectives Association v. City of Dearborn Heights; January 21 1971
- Berkeley Police Officers Association and City of Berkeley, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Matter of Arbitration between City of Dearborn, Michigan and International Association of Fire Fighters Local 412, AFL-CIO, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Arbitration between International Union of District 50 Allied and Technical Workers of the US and Canada and Chippewa County Board of Commissioners, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  December 15 1970
- Matter of Arbitration between the City of Birmingham, Michigan and Birmingham Firefighters Association, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- State of Michigan Employment Relations Commission, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  City of Big rapids and Big Rapids International Association of Fire Fighters; December 9 1970
- Dearborn Heights Officers' Association v. City of Dearborn Heights, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Dearborn Heights Lieutenants Sergeants Corporals and Detectives Association; January 13 1971
- State of Michigan Employment Relations Commission, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  City of St. Joseph, Michigan and Local 1670, International Association of Fire Fighters, AFL-CIO; July 14 1970
- Matter of Arbitration between The Flint Fire Fighters Association, Local 352, International Association of Fire Fighters, AFL-CIO ad the City of Flint, Michigan, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  August 21, 1970
- Midland Police Officers Association and City of Midland, Michigan, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  April 23 1970
- State of Michigan Department of Labor Employment Relations Commission, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  City of Escanaba Public Employer and International Association of Firefighters Local 443 Employee Representative
- State of Michigan Department of Labor Employment Relations Commission, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  City of Muskegon and Muskegon Fire Fighters International Union of Fire Fighters Local No. 370
- State of Michigan Employment Relations Commission, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  City of Marysville, Michigan and Employees of the Marysville Police Department represented by the Fraternal Order of Police
- State of Michigan Employment Relations Commission Statutory Arbitration, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Flint Police Captains' Association and The City of Flint, a Municipal Corporation
- City of Ironwood and Ironwood Police Officer's Association, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  August 31 1970
- Clawson Police Officers Association v. City od Clawson, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  December 10 1970
- Matter of Arbitration between City of Dearborn, Michigan and International Association of Fire Fighters Local 412, AFL-CIO, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Pennsylvania Police Arbitration, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Wisconsin Public Employee Arbitration Cases, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Wisconsin Employment Relations Commission Arbitration Cases, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- State of Michigan Department of Labor Employment Relations Commission Arbitration Cases, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Public Employee Arbitration Cases in New York and Michigan, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Suggested Amendments to Public Employee Relations Acts, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  2 reports commissioned for Governor Romney for the amendment of PERA